Spencer Olson

https://www.linkedin.com/in/spencer-olson-a35a33204

3300 Camino Real Trl, Denton, Tx 76208

(469) - 215 - 8372

<u>SpencerOlson2@my.unt.edu</u> <u>Spencer51902@gmail.com</u>

PROJECTS

NASA Ocean Project

September 2023 - Current

Member of the NASA Ocean Project. In addition to planning, problem-solving, and helping in task management, I have been responsible for the input integration of OSC to Unity for data collection and usage as well as currently working on webcam streaming for the use of skeletal tracking. In addition, I am responsible for supplying specification documents for various project areas.

VR RC Car Project

September 2023 - December 2023

In September of 2023, a graduate student from the College of Engineering requested my aid in constructing an RC car that could be controlled completely in the VR Space. Using a combination of microcontrollers, cameras, 3D Printed materials, and a VR headset we created a successful prototype that we then programmed in Unity to be controlled using the headset and VR controllers.

Untitled Behavioral Analysis Graduate Dissertation Game

January 2024 - Current

In January of 2024, I was approached by a graduate student in the bio-med engineering department who wanted to create a video game that could measure user behavior for their thesis. I signed on as the chief narrative writer and program consultant as well as a gameplay programmer for the project.

EXPERIENCE

Walmart, 2750 W University Dr, Denton, TX 76201 - Associate in Fresh/Cap 2

January 2021 - March 2022

Worked at the Walmart location on W University Dr in Denton working as a Fresh/Cap 2 associate. This includes stocking, capping, inventory, and any other task needed to be done in both the produce and meat sections.

The University of North Texas, 3940 N Elm St, Denton, TX 76207 - Games and Simulations Programmer/Developer

March 2022 - July 2022

Worked in a grant-funded program that developed VR programs to aid neurological research. Using the Unity engine and C# coding language I worked to create a base VR space that could be used for testing. Work included creating a C# base physics, interactable buttons/doors, and realistic collision. The project was ended due to a lack of funding

SKILLS

Proficient in C++, C#, Java, Python, Javascript, and Swift coding languages.

Great work ethic and a team player.

Knowledgeable in Microsoft Office.

Multiple projects completed in both Unity and Unreal 4/5

Familiar with Xcode, Visual Studio, and several other IDEs

SUMMARY

Creative problem solver and team player. Passionate about developing new skills and refining old ones. I love to code and am constantly finding ways to implement this love into other projects.

The University of North Texas, 1506 W Highland St, Denton, TX 76203 -Spark Training Coordinator SS3

July 2022 - Current

Currently employed for the Spark Makerspace for UNT, providing aid to patrons, creating and developing projects, and maintaining the space. Skills required include A/V, Soldering, Laser Cutting/Engraving, 3D Printing, Electronics, and Programming. Projects I worked on in the Space include a VR Walkthrough of the Space, a Board Game of my design, and aiding other makers with their projects. As a training coordinator, I am also responsible for ensuring the skills of the makers, and getting them prepared for teaching patrons. I am also responsible for scheduling training, documenting, and developing training programs.

EDUCATION

Lone Star High School, 2606 Panther Creek Pkwy, Frisco, TX 75033 — *High School Diploma, Cum Laude*

August 2016 - May 2020

Graduated Cum Laude with STEM and Computer Science endorsements as well as the AP Scholar accolade

The University of North Texas, 502 N Texas Blvd, Denton, TX 76201 — Senior

August 2020 - Present

Enrolled with the general admission scholarship, I am on a four-year track to graduate with a major in computer science and a certificate in game design.